Sanjay Nambiar

Game Programmer

_

PROJECTS

The Draft | UCF FIEA, Orlando — Lead Programmer

DECEMBER 2016 - PRESENT

Developed core game flow control and global event system in Unreal Engine 4.15.

Implemented RTS style unit controller with path finding in C++ and Blueprints.

Designed and implemented interactions between animation state machine and AI behaviors.

Setup code quality guidelines and mentored team of 5 programmers in software architecture and C++ implementation in Unreal Engine.

Worked in a multi disciplinary team of 15 consisting of artists and producers and coordinated between the other team leads for sprint planning, design and task prioritization.

Anonymous Engine | UCF FIEA, Orlando — *Programmer*

JANUARY 2016 - APRIL 2017

A data driven game engine built in C++ 11 with unit tests and doxygen documentation.

The engine has basic scripting support through XML with expression parsers and supports OpenGL and DirectX rendering.

Ghost Chamber | UCF FIEA, Orlando — Programmer

JANUARY 2016 - APRIL 2017

An interactive hologram software plugin for AutoCAD software in C# and Kinect libraries. Team of 3 programmers, 1 producer and an artist.

A custom hardware with onboard Raspberry Pi was built to display the hologram in a glass pyramid.

Rapid Prototypes | UCF FIEA, Orlando — *Programmer*

SEPTEMBER 2016 - NOVEMBER 2016

5 two week game prototypes made in teams of 5 using Flash, Unity and Unreal Engine. Worked on gameplay and scripted animations.

Verlet Physics System | Personal — Programmer

JUNE 2016

Verlet based physics system with basic physics constraints, simple cloth physics in C++, rendered using OpenGL.

(407) 579-3576 sanjay.mnambiar@gmail.com www.sanjaynambiar.net

SKILLS

Languages: C, C++, C#, 68000 assembly, Java

Engines: Unity, Unreal Engine 4

Version Control: Git, Perforce,

Subversion

IDEs: Visual Studio, IntelliJ

Frameworks: OpenGL, OpenCV, Vuforia for Unity, Steam VR

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Amazon

APR 2015 - JUNE 2016

Designed and developed software for compliance screening Amazon sellers.

Setup code quality guidelines for multiple teams.

Software Engineer | IBM

JUNE 2011 - MARCH 2015

Developed a custom business intelligence reporting framework for IBM Fiberlink

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida,Orlando — M.S. in Interactive Entertainment

AUGUST 2016 - DECEMBER 2017

Amrita School of Engineering, India — B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

JUNE 2007 - MAY 2011

4 year undergraduate program equivalent to B.S. in Computer Science.